<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Wade Allen</title>
        <description>Navigating Ministry, Leadership, and Life</description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 15:52:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 15:52:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.3.4</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Following Paul's Pattern of Ministry</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I love the book of Acts because Luke guides us through the history of the early church, allowing us to grasp how early Christians followed God’s guidance. By reflecting on their actions, we gain insight into what it means to live according to God’s will each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Acts 17, Paul and his companions arrive in Thessalonica, where, as noted in verses 1-2, Paul regularly ministers in the synagogue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(Acts 17:1–2 NIV) When Paul and his companions had passed through Amphipolis and Apollonia, they came to Thessalonica, where there was a Jewish synagogue. As was his custom, Paul went into the synagogue, and on three Sabbath days he reasoned with them from the Scriptures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phrase &lt;em&gt;as was his custom&lt;/em&gt; highlights that Paul frequently engaged in this type of ministry, utilizing the synagogue as a venue to share about Jesus with those seeking God—a practice reminiscent of Jesus, who also frequented the synagogue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(Luke 4:16 NIV) He went to Nazareth, where he had been brought up, and on the Sabbath day he went into the synagogue, as was his custom…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Paul, the synagogue is a vital setting for sharing Jesus’ message. Similarly, as pastors, the church serves as an essential place for us to share, reason, build relationships, and fulfill our God-given ministry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Paul’s ministry extends beyond the synagogue. In verse 17, we see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(Acts 17:17 NIV11-GK) So he reasoned in the synagogue with both Jews and God-fearing Greeks, as well as in the marketplace day by day with those who happened to be there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also engages with Epicurean and Stoic philosophers and speaks at the Areopagus, demonstrating the importance of being present in public spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul’s daily routines remind us that our work should be a balance between sacred and secular settings. As pastors, we may find ourselves primarily in church, interacting mainly with church members since our salary originates there; this can lead to misunderstandings about our work ethic when we are not in the office. But what if we envisioned our ministry as encompassing both the church and the outside world? What if we recognized our interactions with non-religious people as equally significant as those within the church?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we reflect on work-life balance, we should also consider balance in our ministry contexts. This means allocating our time and energy between sacred and secular spaces, or perhaps considering all spaces as sacred. For instance, the gym could serve as an intentional environment to connect with others for the sake of Jesus, while activities like joining a mountain bike group or having dinner with neighbors might also be viewed as part of our ministry. Jesus and Paul both understood the value of engaging in both the synagogue and the marketplace. How well are we balancing our lives to be present in both arenas?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/following-pauls-pattern-of-ministry</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/following-pauls-pattern-of-ministry</guid>
                
                <category>work-life-balance</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Pastor's Sick Day</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I got sick - on a Saturday afternoon, of all times. For a pastor, this is perhaps the most challenging time to fall ill. Thankfully, we are a multi-staffed church. I called our associate pastor, emailed my sermon, and witnessed God’s provision unfold. He did a phenomenal job, and by afternoon my phone was filled with texts offering prayers for healing and appreciation for his ministry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many pastors, handing off a sermon just hours before worship simply isn’t an option. This experience caused me to reflect deeply on my role and function at the church. Being temporarily incapacitated raised important questions about what I should and shouldn’t be doing. And yes, it made me consider the classic “what if I get hit by a bus?” scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question strikes at the heart of ministry sustainability and work-life balance. Even as a solo pastor in a small church, we should strive to be surrounded by capable people who can step into any aspect of our work. Imagine creating a spreadsheet of everything we do - there should be very few blank spaces in the “backup” column for each task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I confess there were seasons when I over-functioned in ministry. My hands were in everything - from printing bulletins to setting up the church WiFi. I updated the website, led most meetings, and was the last one to lock up the building. For some pastors, these tasks are simply expected. But maintaining a healthy work-life balance becomes nearly impossible under such circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t pretend to have all the answers for shifting away from this dynamic. In my case, it required changing ministry contexts. When I began my new pastorate, I intentionally avoided falling into the pattern of doing everything. If you’re reading this and identifying with this description, I challenge you to consider how you might begin shifting this reality in your context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, none of us will get hit by a bus. But my prayer for you - for every pastor - is that you would find fulfillment in all aspects of life, not just church work. Let’s be intentional about planning for our absence. When we do, the church will be stronger, healthier, and more aligned with God’s vision for His body.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/the-pastors-sick-day</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/the-pastors-sick-day</guid>
                
                <category>work-life-balance</category>
                
                <category>sick</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Leading with Timeless Truths: Reflections on Same as Ever</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As the new year begins, I take a moment to reflect on the books I’ve read last year and identify those I’d like to explore this year. One notable recommendation for 2024 is Morgan Housel’s book &lt;em&gt;Same as Ever: A Guide to What Never Changes&lt;/em&gt;, which I highly suggest for church leaders. The key theme of the book emphasizes that timeless truths can guide us through cultural shifts. In a rapidly changing world, it’s valuable to remember the constant aspects of human behavior, such as fear, greed, and adaptability. While our culture evolves, it is refreshing to contemplate what remains unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In chapter 8, Housel highlights the significance of stories and narratives, a topic that resonates with preaching and leadership. He explains how compelling stories draw people in and can profoundly influence our thinking. Considering the Bible as a narrative reinforces the idea that such stories shape our community. I am reminded of the crucial role storytelling plays in preaching, which, while not new, is an important aspect that endures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our church family is currently engaged in a discernment process regarding the use of a significant financial gift to our church. Opinions on how to use or save this money differ, and our discernment team will host an informational meeting for the congregation this week. While exploring various possibilities and allowing members to share their views is important, it is crucial that we focus on sharing the story of the team’s efforts and insights. Stories hold power, and recounting how God has worked in our conversations, meetings, and discussions can unite and transform opinions. Ultimately, the question should not be &lt;em&gt;What do I think we should do?&lt;/em&gt;, but rather &lt;em&gt;What does God want us to do?&lt;/em&gt; To achieve this, we need to emphasize storytelling and communicate effectively about it. As Housel might say, &lt;em&gt;this has always been the case and always will be&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book offers various insights and applications for those in church ministry. Here are a few to consider, making it a valuable addition to your reading list for 2025:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Predictability of Human Behavior&lt;/strong&gt;: Human behavior tends to be predictable due to core emotions like fear and greed that are consistent across generations, helping navigate congregational dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Long Game in Leadership&lt;/strong&gt;: Success usually stems from long-term efforts rather than immediate gains, highlighting the value of patience in ministry.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Role of Uncertainty and Ambiguity&lt;/strong&gt;: Resilience and adaptability are essential in facing an uncertain future, encouraging faith over fear of the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoiding Short-Term Thinking&lt;/strong&gt;: Short-term decisions can undermine long-term health, prompting a focus on sustainable growth rather than immediate results.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Power of Perspective&lt;/strong&gt;: Small shifts in perspective can transform how challenges are viewed, helping congregants see trials as growth opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resilience Through Consistency&lt;/strong&gt;: While the world changes, constants like hard work and humility remain essential, reinforcing the importance of spiritual disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Seduction of Extremes&lt;/strong&gt;: Balancing extremes leads to better outcomes, encouraging thoughtful decision-making and conflict resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust as the Ultimate Currency&lt;/strong&gt;: Trust is vital in healthy relationships, necessitating transparency and integrity in leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wealth vs. Richness&lt;/strong&gt;: True wealth is about time and freedom, prompting a focus on eternal priorities over material accumulation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Compounding Power of Small Actions&lt;/strong&gt;: Consistent small actions yield significant results over time, emphasizing everyday faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/leading-with-timeless-truths-reflections-on-same-as-ever</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/leading-with-timeless-truths-reflections-on-same-as-ever</guid>
                
                <category>leadership</category>
                
                <category>discernment</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Assistive AI vs. Generative AI</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was listening to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://appstories.net/episodes/414&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; from App Stories today, in which the hosts were discussing AI. I found their conversation helpful as we consider how to utilize this new technology in ministry contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hosts were opposed to the use of Generative AI, while they found incredible value in Assistive AI. Let’s discuss the differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One definition of Generative AI describes it this way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Generative AI refers to artificial intelligence systems that can create new content by learning patterns from existing data and generating novel outputs that maintain the statistical properties and characteristics of the training data while being original and unique. These systems use complex neural networks and machine learning algorithms to understand and replicate patterns in various forms of data, including text, images, audio, video, and code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is certainly a mouthful. What does this mean? In short, it has to do with &lt;em&gt;generating content&lt;/em&gt; like text or images, even audio and video. In a ministry context, this sort of AI might be used to write sermons or articles. The hosts of my podcast felt that this sort of AI is unethical or immoral as it &lt;em&gt;artificially&lt;/em&gt; creates content. As we considered in previous blog entries, we need to be careful not to allow a computer to replace our human creativity. We understand that we are made in God’s image, are empowered by the Holy Spirit, and serve as God’s agents in our ministry context. We must bring our full selves to our creative tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, we must be careful to resist Generative AI that replaces our God-given tasks of creating and expressing God’s truth to our congregations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what about Assistive AI? One source defines it this way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Assistive AI refers to artificial intelligence systems designed to augment and enhance human capabilities rather than replace them. These systems work alongside humans, providing support, suggestions, and automation of specific tasks while maintaining human agency and control over the final decisions and outcomes. The primary goal is to make human work more efficient, accurate, and effective through intelligent assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds better, right? Our humanity is preserved in this type of AI. So what kinds of ministry work might fall into this category? As I write this article, my computer offers predictive suggestions for my typing. This is a form of Assistive AI. Spell and grammar checks might also fall into this category. Perhaps we could learn to write computer code to automate specific tasks. Assistive AI might help us write accurate and efficient code. We could delve a little deeper to have AI analyze data or even summarize large amounts of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what are the key characteristics of Assistive AI? First of all, it works &lt;em&gt;alongside&lt;/em&gt; human input, enhancing rather than replacing our human work. Secondly, this sort of AI maintains human control along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we have discussed the value of using AI to maintain work-life balance, it is important to understand the difference between Generative and Assistive AI. I would encourage you to take a few minutes to listen to this short &lt;a href=&quot;https://appstories.net/episodes/414&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; to guide you in your discernment of AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have found great value in utilizing AI in ministry. But at the same time, I find some uses inappropriate for our work as pastors. Let’s keep discussing how we might make good use of this technology without sacrificing our humanity and Holy Spirit-empowered work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/assistive-ai-vs-generative-ai</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/assistive-ai-vs-generative-ai</guid>
                
                <category>ai</category>
                
                <category>moral</category>
                
                <category>ethical</category>
                
                <category>technology</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ethical and Moral Implications of Using AI in Ministry: Part Three</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;In the first two parts of this blog series, I explored the definition of Artificial Intelligence and considered the implications of using this technology in a ministry setting. While it is crucial to carefully consider the theological framework of our humanity, could there be a way to harness Artificial Intelligence for good? Most technology can be deemed both dangerous and helpful, evil and good, destructive and life-giving. So how do we navigate the emergence of AI in our work as pastors?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me offer a few suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it is important to embrace AI with purpose. We must understand it as a tool for enhancing, not replacing, human interaction. We should ask which aspects of our work could benefit from the automation that AI provides. Could the efficiencies provided by AI free up time to spend in conversation? Instead of spending time in the office doing administrative work, could we be freed to take more walks and engage in more one-on-one interactions? More conversations around AI could prove to be helpful among pastors. Let’s share ideas, concerns, potential uses, and areas we should protect from AI. Could there be a best practices guidebook for pastors and AI? In what ways might we establish accountability among pastors as ever-increasing temptations to replace our ministry with AI surface?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, we must provide education and training for ministry leaders in the realm of Artificial Intelligence. AI technology is evolving and changing at rapid rates. Ministry leaders must be equipped with the knowledge to make informed decisions about AI. It is important to encourage a culture of continuous learning regarding these technologies. Clergy groups, colloquiums, and denominational gatherings could all serve as important centers of dialogue around AI. Let’s keep talking and sharing ideas with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, let’s land on a few basic points as we conclude this short series of posts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AI is an aid to human-driven ministry. We must not let it overstep the boundaries of what God has called us to do in ministry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May we begin to create ethical roadmaps for the use of Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s work together for transparent, accountable use of AI in our work. As resources develop, may we carefully delve into them together, keeping a close eye on our theological framework of humanity and the practical uses for ministry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May God give us the wisdom and discernment to learn, grow, critique, and utilize the tools given to us in our time.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/ethical-and-moral-implications-of-using-ai-in-ministry-part-three</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/ethical-and-moral-implications-of-using-ai-in-ministry-part-three</guid>
                
                <category>ai</category>
                
                <category>moral</category>
                
                <category>ethical</category>
                
                <category>technology</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ethical and Moral Implications of Using AI in Ministry: Part Two</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;In the first post on this subject, we explored the ethical and moral considerations of incorporating AI in ministry, examining both the opportunities and challenges it presents. It is important that we thoughtfully discern the complexities of this evolving technology. The first post highlights the complexity of the subject. In this second post, I would like to consider the human role versus the technological role in spiritual work, highlighting the danger of depending too much on technology as pastors. At the same time, I would also like to consider the advantages of harnessing technology for administrative tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we consider our work as pastors, we must be careful not to neglect the personal human touch of ministry. God has made us in His image, &lt;em&gt;imago Dei&lt;/em&gt;, and calls us to live in relationship with people as we follow His example of the Incarnation. As John writes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;John 1:14 (NIV): The Word became flesh and made His dwelling among us. We have seen His glory, the glory of the one and only Son, who came from the Father, full of grace and truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus is God made flesh and come to dwell among us. As we consider the ways that God &lt;em&gt;could have&lt;/em&gt; revealed Himself to us, we understand Jesus &lt;em&gt;come among us&lt;/em&gt; as the way God chose to work. In the same way, we cannot separate our work as pastors from our flesh, our humanity. Therefore, we must be careful in our use of AI, making sure that we do not allow our humanity (including our creative capacity) to be outsourced. &lt;strong&gt;In what areas of our work must we resist the use of AI?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hope is to have a discussion among pastors in our Spring colloquium. But for now, I would suggest that work such as blog/article writing, sermon preparation, personal emails about spiritual matters, and matters of prayer and discernment about the direction of the church be void of AI technology. We might be tempted to incorporate AI into such work, but we must be careful not to allow anything artificial to do this important &lt;em&gt;human&lt;/em&gt; work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, other areas of administration may be greatly enhanced with the use of Artificial Intelligence. What might these areas be? Again, I hope to broaden this conversation in our Spring meeting, but for now, might I suggest a few. While writing should be fully human, might AI serve to check our writing for grammar and style improvements? Could AI be used to generate summaries or condensed versions of our writings for specific purposes, such as sharing information with a worship planning team? What about scheduling, database management, or other administrative tasks that often rob pastors of precious relationship-building time? &lt;strong&gt;Where do we draw the line and learn to utilize technology to assist us in the work of ministry?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to write an additional post on this subject to consider practical ways to answer these questions. For now, let’s consider the theological issues at hand and carefully reflect on the boundaries we should set for this new technology. I look forward to further discussion around these issues in the spring. But for now, let’s give careful consideration to how we approach the opportunities and the dangers of Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/ethical-and-moral-implications-of-using-ai-in-ministry-part-two</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/ethical-and-moral-implications-of-using-ai-in-ministry-part-two</guid>
                
                <category>ai</category>
                
                <category>moral</category>
                
                <category>ethical</category>
                
                <category>technology</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ethical and Moral Implications of Using AI in Ministry: Part One</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;AI, or Artificial Intelligence, is all the rage these days. Investors are pouring resources into research and development across various areas of AI. Smartphones and computers are integrating AI into the very fabric of our workflows. So how do we assess the value and implications of using AI in ministry? This is a complex topic with varying degrees of nuance and implications. Certainly, it would be impossible to adequately cover this topic in one blog post. Therefore, I plan to explore this topic in a series of posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let’s consider the definition of AI. ChatGPT provides this definition:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI) refers to the simulation of human intelligence in machines that are programmed to think like humans and mimic their actions. This may include learning, reasoning, problem-solving, perception, language understanding, and other cognitive capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right away, we may find ourselves uncomfortable with a few words in this definition. Words like &lt;em&gt;simulate&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;mimic&lt;/em&gt; immediately feel inauthentic. Humanity is an essential theological tenet in which we, as Christians, believe that we are made in the image of God. Anything that &lt;em&gt;mimics&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;simulates&lt;/em&gt; seems to fall short of the &lt;em&gt;image of God&lt;/em&gt; presence we bring to ministry. So how can we sort out the ethical, moral, and practical perspectives of using AI in ministry? And how might we find &lt;em&gt;responsible uses&lt;/em&gt; of AI in ministry?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, let’s consider the ways AI is used in ministry settings. At least one church has developed a chatbot that answers theological questions and provides guidance for parishioners seeking direction. I must admit, this sort of AI is difficult to reconcile. Some pastors use AI to generate sermons, which again raises red flags of plagiarism. We may be quick to dismiss AI as incompatible with ministry as we explore such uses. The crucial nature of the human touch in ministry must be considered, and a lack of authenticity and sincerity may cause us to shy away from its use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But could there be responsible uses of AI in ministry that help ministry leaders be more efficient with administrative tasks, having the opportunity to carve out more time for relationship building? Or could AI provide advantages that help pastors spend more time in spiritual and physical renewal? How can we learn to use AI to more effectively communicate and organize? These questions must be asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post serves as an introduction to the complexity of this topic. Next week, we will continue the discussion of AI in ministry. As pastors, we must carefully consider the ethical and moral implications of new technologies. At the same time, the exploration of possibilities might prove to free us for greater work.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/ethical-and-moral-implications-of-using-ai-in-ministry-part-one</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/ethical-and-moral-implications-of-using-ai-in-ministry-part-one</guid>
                
                <category>ai</category>
                
                <category>moral</category>
                
                <category>ethical</category>
                
                <category>technology</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Office Dilemma: Balancing Presence and Productivity in Ministry</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;We are rethinking our workspaces on our church property, potentially repurposing a staff office to expand our welcome area. The planning discussions have been intriguing, revealing how little time we actually spend in the office. This doesn’t mean we seldom work; rather, our work often occurs offsite. We frequently meet for lunches and walks to connect with people, and even our “office” work often takes place in coffee shops and quiet spaces away from the church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I reflect on my workflow, I realize I do my best work away from the church. Creative work at my office desk is nearly impossible due to constant interruptions and difficulty focusing. However, a short walk to a coffee shop significantly enhances my productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As church leaders, how do we address this? It’s crucial to be present for hallway conversations with staff and church members, and to be available for quick interactions. Yet, when do these encounters hinder our best work? How do we balance time in the office with time in more productive environments?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am looking forward to deeper conversations about these dynamics at our spring colloquium. Different patterns might be necessary based on personality types, learning styles, church environments, and congregational expectations. Nonetheless, I find it essential to leave the office to do my best work. I encourage pastors pursuing work-life balance to consider this dynamic. Too often, a lack of intentionality in this area can stall our progress. May we feel both the freedom and the responsibility to evaluate our environments so that we can focus on the work God has called us to do.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/the-office-dilemma-balancing-presence-and-productivity-in-ministry</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/the-office-dilemma-balancing-presence-and-productivity-in-ministry</guid>
                
                <category>leadership</category>
                
                <category>office</category>
                
                <category>life-balance</category>
                
                <category>productivity</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Abraham Lincoln’s Enduring Example of Leadership and Growth</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Having lived for nearly a decade in Springfield, Illinois, I am an unapologetic Lincoln admirer. While his story is synonymous with the American story, from the poor log cabin to the presidency, Lincoln embodies our hopes to move beyond our present condition. At the same time, Lincoln’s strong leadership during one of our country’s most difficult seasons offers guidance to all leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently finished a new book (2022) on Lincoln by Jon Meacham entitled &lt;em&gt;And There Was Light: Abraham Lincoln and the American Struggle&lt;/em&gt;. Meacham chronicles Lincoln’s life in terms of his understanding and reaction to slavery. Lincoln’s views would be considered draconian by today’s standards, but he continued to learn and open his heart to what he considered God’s guidance and providence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I read this book, I found it particularly applicable to anyone who leads an organization, including pastors. I found his actions courageous and challenging. He never seemed to take the easy way out. Rather, he acted as if he were achieving a higher purpose. At the same time, he used his wit and relational skills to convince his opponents to join him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love history and especially enjoy historical biographies, so I tend to like these sorts of books. I found this book enlightening. I was often surprised by the historical details that I hadn’t previously known, and my respect for Lincoln only increased upon reading it. Meacham is a gifted author and leads the reader carefully through the story. You will not be disappointed if you decide to read this book.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/abraham-lincoln-s-enduring-example-of-leadership-and-growth</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/abraham-lincoln-s-enduring-example-of-leadership-and-growth</guid>
                
                <category>leadership</category>
                
                <category>book</category>
                
                <category>lincoln</category>
                
                <category>courage</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Lessons from Acts 6 on Delegation and Focus</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;During the fall, I have been working my way through the Book of Acts. I find this detailed account of the early church’s beginnings fascinating. In chapter 6, we encounter a dynamic that speaks to our work in ministry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we see people in the church complaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Acts 6:1 (NIV): In those days when the number of disciples was increasing, the Hellenistic Jews among them complained against the Hebraic Jews because their widows were being overlooked in the daily distribution of food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you believe that people are bringing complaints to the leaders? I’m sure this has never happened to you (detect the sarcasm?). While we sometimes joke about the insignificant nature of many complaints, these criticisms are valid. People are going without food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us are quick to resolve such matters, even if it means working longer hours. Faithful leaders often step in at the expense of personal health to ensure everyone is served. Yet, this is not how the apostles handled the situation. They quickly identified the danger of trying to do too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Acts 6:2 (NIV): So the Twelve gathered all the disciples together and said, “It would not be right for us to neglect the ministry of the word of God in order to wait on tables.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They turned to the congregation and insisted that workers step forward to ensure all are served.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Acts 6:3–4 (NIV): Brothers and sisters, choose seven men from among you who are known to be full of the Spirit and wisdom. We will turn this responsibility over to them and will give our attention to prayer and the ministry of the word.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice the wisdom in this statement: &lt;em&gt;choose…from among you…&lt;/em&gt; What a powerful message for pastors striving for work-life balance. We must learn to turn to the congregation and ask for help. We cannot do it all on our own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This action is not because we are lazy or afraid of hard work. Rather, it is a dedication to the primary work in our calling: &lt;em&gt;prayer and the ministry of the word.&lt;/em&gt; These are the tasks that should be central to our work. When we find ourselves slipping outside of this focus, we must be cautious. It is sometimes appropriate for us as pastors to serve meals or take on menial tasks. But we need to be careful not to allow this sort of work to become our primary focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apostles knew that saying &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;waiting on tables&lt;/em&gt; meant saying &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;prayer and the ministry of the word.&lt;/em&gt; As we do the work of ministry, we must hold on to such wisdom. We must be willing to ask others to pitch in and do the work of serving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One final point: This action produced growth in the church. We read in verse 7,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Acts 6:7 (NIV): So the word of God spread. The number of disciples in Jerusalem increased rapidly, and a large number of priests became obedient to the faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of the apostles’ laser focus, the church grew and spread. Would this have happened if the leaders were sidetracked? Maybe, maybe not. Acts 6 reminds us to pay attention to our primary work and to call on others to help carry the work of ministry. May we keep this in mind as we strive for work-life balance.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/lessons-from-acts-6-on-delegation-and-focus</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/lessons-from-acts-6-on-delegation-and-focus</guid>
                
                <category>boundaries</category>
                
                <category>acts</category>
                
                <category>wisdom</category>
                
                <category>focus</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>